BRANDON CRUZ

BRANDONRCRUZ@GMAIL.COM

OBJECTIVE

I am a customer-orientated IT professional with over 10 years of technical experience. I am seeking a challenging Systems & Networking Administration position with an organization that can effectively use my skills and knowledge. My experience includes Networking Administration, Desktop and Help Desk Support, Server Management, Active Directory and more. I am currently enrolled to finish my Bachelor's degree in Network and Server Administration.

EDUCATION

Western Governors University, Online

Major: Bachelor of Science in Information Technology – Network Administration

Current – ETA Graduation Date of November 2016

Tompkins Cortland Community College, Dryden NY

Major: Computer Support Specialist, CIS

August 2004 - May 2006

Courses include Computer Hardware Repair/Maintenance and Help Desk/User Support. Currently studying for CompTIA A+ Certification and to be certified as a Microsoft Desktop Support Specialist.

Certifications

CIW Web Foundations Associate

CIW License CIW ID 509300 April 2012

CompTIA A+

CompTIA License 8JZ4BKXCXKVE2XS5 October 2012 to April 2017

CompTIA Project+

CompTIA License 90WGC16C83F4CW59 April 2013

CompTIA Network+

CompTIA License OWSZMLEDZGE42BBR October 2013 to April 2017

CompTIA Security+

CompTIA License LY1PGP8LRCQ11QJK April 2014 to April 2017

Skills

- -Active Directory
- -Microsoft SCCM
- -Microsoft SCSM
- -Microsoft SCORCH
- -Microsoft System
- Center
- -Cisco IOS
- -SQL DB
- Administration
- -Network
- Administration &
- Security
- -DHCP/DNS/WINS
- -Group Policy
- Administration
- -Antivirus McAfee
- EPO/MSEP
- -WSUS
- -File/Print Services
- -MS Office Suite
- 2003, 2007, 2010,
- 2013
- -Imaging &
- Deployment via
- SCCM/Altiris/Ghost
- -VMWare
- -Service Delivery
- -Fluke Optiview XG
- -AirMagnet Wi-Fi
- Surveyor & Wi-Fi
- Analyzer
- -IIS
- -File/Share
- Permissions &
- Security

Programming

- -CSS
- -HTML/XHTML
- -JavaScript
- -PHP
- -Some SQL/Java
- -XML
- -C++
- -Visual Basic.NET
- -PowerShell

OS

EXPERIENCE

-AS400/IBM iSeries -Windows 10/8/7/XP -Windows Server 2012/2008/2003 -Linux/Ubuntu

Sr. Client Technologies Specialist I – Enterprise IT BorgWarner Morse TEC, Ithaca, New York

March 2007 – Present

Primarily responsible for IT Customer environment. Execute task to enhance and support the desktop environment, provides specialized IT services (e.g. high level meeting support, root-cause analysis, customer consulting), and provides IT facility related services (e.g. audio-visual environment, security systems, printers/copiers).

Tasks Include

- Involved with all IT related Projects as Technical Lead. Past Projects included Verizon/AT&T DAS installation, Campus Fiber Upgrades, IDF Cabinet upgrades, VoIP Implementation, Cisco WLC upgrade
- Meet with Business to discuss needs from IT Technical aspect
- Troubleshooting LAN/WAN/WLAN Issues
- * Network Latency issues
- * Network Wiring issues
- * Access Point coverage issues
- Installing and configuring Cisco Network switches, routers, and access points
- * Cisco 2900 &1800 series switches
- * Cisco Controller based WLAN & Autonomous Aps
- Administration to Global Microsoft SCSM environment for BorgWarner. Tasks include maintenance and upgrades to SCSM environment including orchestrator runbooks and PowerShell scripting to help end user and technician experience
- Administration of various Application and license servers
- Executes the desktop services and standards (e.g. hardware/software, data locations, etc)
- Executes the deployment process and desktop image components
- Ensures that remote and on-site support issues are resolved to customers satisfaction
- Maintains software version control (application and system)
- Maintains License Management.
- Maintains client security settings (e.g. admin rights, software installs, etc)
- Maintains customer configuration options (e.g. screensavers, page layout views, etc) and incorporate into the BorgWarner Desktop image
- Maintains client asset inventory, disposal, and refresh plans

IT STAP Student - Intern

July 2002 - March 2007

BorgWarner Morse TEC, Ithaca, New York

Responsible for various PC repairs and troubleshooting, setting up PCs, various networking tasks, implementing Altiris for PC images, managing users & computers in Active Directory, managing mailboxes on Exchange servers, managing user accounts in Team Center Engineering, managing user accounts/devices in AS400, running payrolls including account payable, factory, exempt and non-exempt, and various projects including Exchange migration from Exchange 5.5 to 2003.